By the way, we're halfway through the
perfection of giving, and we're going to talk
now about what giving is. It says it
means people who have nothing and
who don't have much
money. It means
insects, it means
ants. This is something I used to do with my
friends, and the only thing we could eat there
were French fries. The salad at that
time was horrible, very
bad. We would buy some fries and
sit down and feed the
birds. It's really something fun; it's a very fun
meditation.
When you buy something, you sit and
feed the
birds. You have it in your hand,
and then these birds come. You talk to
the birds and say, "If you eat
this, you will be my student when I
become..."
and then you give them a little piece of potato. They
always eat it. Who else did that?
Mr.
Boo gave his meat to the tigress. "If you
eat this, you
will be..." and the four babies and the mother
were his students, his five students. I
think that's something fun. There are
many ways you
can give and do the parables. You don't
need to take everything so seriously.
Try to always remember.
You can
also... at the same time, I think...  You have fun
with them. You will be a much better
bis. Think of the ways
you can have fun and do things for
other beings and also have fun. You can
do it throughout the
day, simply when you see
people, when you go to the airport.
Do small things for them, like making sure
they are first in line and the toilet
is clean when you go in.
Sampa means a little bit of
rye flour. This is the perfection of giving. You do
n't have to
think, "I have to give my body" or something
similar; just small things.
Now, remember that you are a saved body.
Perhaps that is more productive for
us and a better practice for
us. And that is. It
means daughter or son of the Buddhas; it is a
synonym for bisa.
He
says, "
Sit down." If there are too many birds and a little
piece of potato is not enough,
then buy a second bag
of potatoes. When you do a small
practice for some animal or someone
similar, make sure they are
satisfied, that they have what they
want. Keep feeding them until
they refuse to eat. Okay, it
means
make sure they get what they
want, even if it's just little pieces of potato.  Being
frisky with money is a little more difficult.
It means we
feel like we're
important when we give something. When we make a
donation, for
example, we think, "Oh, we're so special!
I'm so
generous!" And many times we have some
pride, even in small things we
do. So, say that's it. It
means
you practice your first
perfection. Now, teach yourself to be
proud. Just stop.
And now, yes. In your heart, do
n't think you're so
special. Personally, I feel it's
good to forget once you've done it
and then move on to
do something else. Do
n't stay there thinking about it.
Here's a very
important piece of advice, which is traditional.
This part is
something: Sometimes you get carried away when
giving money, and you give too
much. Maybe it
overwhelms you, but don't regret what you've already
given. When you
regret it, traditionally, you say you
destroy good karma; the seed
fades. And
when you regret it, it's good to say, "
Ah, I got carried away. That's it.
Next time I'll be more careful."
But don't feel regret, and don't
try to get it done again.
Go back,
let it happen. What happens on purpose later on, you wo
n't regret it, you'll be extremely
happy about it.
And if you simply give things
uncontrollably throughout the
day, it
feels
great and you'll get so much more. So don't
worry, just start having
that habit of giving what
you can and do it throughout the
day. My personal experience is that
things keep coming
back, you have much more money than you expected,
and then
use it. There's a very special, strange karma
when you realize that when you give
money to that person, they already had a lot of
money. That happened to me once,
I was
quite upset. Let whatever happens,
first investigate,
but we never
know. Many times we don't know how much
money those people have.
They ask for a lot of money, but maybe for a
reason. Maybe
inside they know.
Once you
give it, don't
worry. It always comes back much more than you
expected.
If you
regret it or think, "Oh, I gave too much,"
it really
is a very nice word
to fix the word for  A classic:
Fix your motivation before giving anything.
So
first think, "I would
like you to be my student when I am."
Even if you just give someone
a few dollars or a cup of coffee
or something similar, just pause in your
mind: "Please, my student, when I
become..." There is a beautiful theme, and there is
a very
beautiful prayer, and it
says, "In the realms of hell, may
people appear and
ask me to be their teacher
in hell, and may I sit there so that
people can ask me to be their teacher."
So when
you say, "Hello, please say a prayer,
may I be the teacher of those
people." It
almost means... You feel like you want to
cry when...
We don't see other things, we can't
see other things
anymore because you can only see... You can't
even see yourself
for 20 minutes. Then when you come out of
that
experience, maybe until you
sleep, you have 10 or 12 more hours. You have
all these incredible ideas.
That's not direct perception in
emptiness. We call that the
aftereffects. Then we
start to have
incredible insights during the
next...  That day, that's dead, but
during that day, try not to go to sleep.
Okay, one of the things you
realize, and
there are understandings you have, is that the prana is
still in your central channel. Some
prana stays there. Then some of
those ideas you have, and each of
them were
organized, were structured in
the four truths of the AH, four
aspects, 16
great ideas. And sometimes they get
corrupted and have become a doctrine,
and sometimes they don't make much
sense, but they
exist. Well, the point is that there are
certain incredible things. And these
understandings that you have once you see
it
directly because the prana is still in the
central channel. For example, you can read
other people's minds to the very
end. But here are
the understandings we have, and perhaps
we should rewrite these 16.
But one of them that we have is that you
never did anything, you never
gave anything selflessly, never, never, you never
really gave anything without expecting
some kind of praise.
That's human nature.
Every time you give something to
someone, that is really a
strong AH, there will always be
a motivation, that you want something
or that you are trying to obtain
Something I don't think you should walk around
depressed about it, but
you should understand if you have a bad
habit,
at least you should understand, okay,
even though you can't
stop, you should understand that habit, and
many times we tend
not to give something unless
we can get something in
return.
So if there are situations where
you can
anonymously, or you can run fast, once you have
given that, it is
something to change your nature before you
become an area. But at least
know a little more about it and then
work. It is nature,
hum, not to do something for someone else without
having interest. It
is
natural, but we must allow one to
perfect
it without expecting that
something should be done.
[Music]
means talking
about the perfection
of the teachings. Bold.
What a shame you can't speak
because you could make some money.
There will be exceptions. They will be able to speak if
I ask
something. It seems I am
safe. Sign: listen about
the gift of dharma in
Buddhism, and it
means don't give it to people. Don't bother people
with your thoughts. Don't bother them with
the good
news. Don't bother them with thoughts that once
you start
studying  Especially with your wife or
husband or your relatives, and you say, "
Oh, he's the true
prophet. He imparted these wonderful things to us,
and you must agree."
If you want your husband or wife
to never become Buddhists, it's
best not to bother them with your Buddhism.
So don't bother them, don't
bother other people with your Buddhism.
Don't try to force it on people who do
n't want to hear it. You can be a Buddhist and
affect people. Be generous for people. Someone
wants to
know. Someone wants to.
So if you simply teach them a
single
verse, a line or two of
Buddhism, that is the gift of faith. That is the
karma of giving the gift of faith, which is the
highest form of
giving.
I have in my life what we call
conflict. I have
time. I have a
choice. Well, I have a
choice. I can translate many more books. I
can teach more things. Many
people want
personal things. I must decide with my
own time. I only have a
limited amount of time. I must make
daily decisions about what I spend
and what I believe in.
Living is a priority for me. To
make sure that I don't disappear from the
world. I believe and think about it.  Many
people ask me, sometimes
people need about 2 or 3
hours for a discussion of some personal problem,
and I have
my mind on it because I know they also
need the time,
but my
time isn't limited. I barely have enough
hours left before going somewhere else.
I have to think about what's more important: how
can I help more people?
So
here's an opportunity to share
the Dharma. That's the highest gift. I
think you can think about it.
You have to think
about whether there's any way to preserve
the Dharma in the world. That's extremely important.
They call it the light of the
world, and I've always heard that in
Christianity you shouldn't
hide the light under a
basket. This
world without these teachings
would truly be darkness; there would be no light.
So I think personally, I think I
should keep some light
before I go. I have to make
sure I leave that light. That
means I don't have much time to
sit and listen. I don't have time. Oh, God, did
n't you learn math in
school? Yes, well, what is 1 times 200,000?
They say 200,000. I say
yes.  Even so, I need an hour, and I say,
"But we have close to 200 students in
our
system. It's completely impossible to
have this capacity. I can't
do it, so please, I have to
make
decisions, and I believe that being able to
maintain the physical karma in it is something I
am capable of and can
do. If they simply share a line
with another person in class, they are already
teaching karma. If they simply
explain
something that someone
says, even if it's
the car going
towards it, it's the same as teaching it. It's the same.
Sharing with another
person personally is the same
as giving a teaching.
I like this
image. She is the one. She
came for work many
years ago.
We were working
overtime when she also
arrived and asked for a job. I
interviewed them and told them, "My advice for you
is to be an
actress because you will never be a
secretary," and your father
thanked me for it. But Melma also came
during that
time. We were working until
midnight, growing the company, and those were
difficult times. I told her, "Look, I'm going
to hire you, but there are no hours." I mean, you
work until I say
no. The first thing she told me was, "There's
a line of people who are..."
Waiting for this interview, I almost took her out
and said, "Okay, thank you, Lu.
I'll contact you, but something told me
that you
can work as many as you
can."
Then she started coming to
classes and became known as
Melma. Camera, her neighborhood in New York,
everyone knows her
now, everywhere.
Then we started calling her
Melma and Lu. People had an
objection: she's not a man, she's not
Tibetan, she doesn't use [something], now she's the only one. She's
not from Asia. How can you
call her Lama? We had many problems regarding this.
Here the text says the great
Lamas
don't need to be
sitting on a
throne. Many Asians to be able to [
be a Lama]—I don't
say it—the
name means that you are teaching
people regardless of the country where
you are from.
Before my teacher's time,
women were not allowed to
study the course. When we
started, we had
many
problems. It
means it's not necessary to sit on the
throne.
That doesn't mean you have to climb to that level.
You can be sitting in an
airplane seat. It's a great
place. They're going to have [something] and they can't
escape, and then the airplane bathrooms
are never
available. It's a
captive audience.  A very simple but
very nice phrase.
The next image. I think we have a
video here.
Francisco is a
video, no,
yeah. He's massaging
it.
Okay, anyway. Tell me if you do, yeah. Okay. Let's
go. This is one of my favorite videos
here.
Francisco is one of the best.
[Music]
What we're looking for in
life.
Us,
things you and
[Music]
is you and I. We got it.
We don't need no
[Music]
more. Even in
the you and I. Can we? Any
before sleep, hear the cricket, see the [
Music]
moon and through,
and no limit to what we can
[Music] do.
We know what we have. Let's hold on tight. What we're looking
for in life.
Us, crazy, but things are fine, right? [
Music]
[Applause]
It's the greatest gift you can give. You want to
do something
important? Then share Dharma. That's
the greatest gift you can give. You
don't need to be perfect. You don't
feel like you have to be perfect.
The imperfect Dharma teachers are
the best because they understand the
deepest problems.
Ah, it's
me
too. They don't feel like they should be some
kind of saint or something.
I think when you teach  The
Dharma. Someone once asked me, "What
's the first thing that happens when you teach
the Dharma?" You reach a new level of
hypocrisy because you're teaching something you can't
do many times
yourself, but inevitably, if you really
speak, now during the Dharma...
So don't think you have to be
perfect, don't wait until you're perfect, do
n't wait too long.
Okay, what you understand, teach. What you do
n't understand, admit it. And say, "
Look, later I'll come back and give you that
answer." And ask someone
else, don't think you have to be
perfect, don't be
proud, don't be ashamed to ask them
a question. Just do it. It's
the highest, most elevated karma
you can
do. If you know someone, the Avi, and you
ask them where you're going to teach, they're
looking for someone who could
sponsor your
teachings. Don't wait
until you're perfect
because that takes a long time. So
teach, and it's
also okay to take risks. And don't just say, "Go ahead,
excuse me,
everyone, and go ahead, move forward."
Grandfather is ready to help
with the second tour. Just let me
know before I spend the money.
Maybe this week they'll want to have it.
So talk to them.
Maybe it's better if they do this week. I
'm happy to be able to make the same
donation.
Very good, very beautiful prayer. And I remember
when I first heard it from my
teacher, and it made me very happy. He said, "
When you are doing your
morning practice, and when you are
doing your mantras and your prayers, don't mute
your lips.
People who do that hear it,
right?" He says, "Say it clearly so that
if someone is sitting next to you, they
can hear you. Unless you are on an
airplane or something, say it
clearly because there are many spirits in the
world, especially here. I think there are
many spirits around. There were many
problems, many disputes between the
white people and the Indians,
the native people of this place.
I think there are many spirits still around here,
and they are curious to know what you
are doing in your cabin. They want to
hear you, so do your things
loudly so they can hear you." And
here is the original source of this.
Many of the things I talk about in the
series come from this
book. Now, this was the milk of the
Quebro.
Spirits around you,
you can also imagine that people
all over the world are sitting around you,
so
imagine that there are many beings
listening to you
because you can't. You will
also have the karma of giving
dharma, which is a karma.
Listen
indiscriminately, so you better have
something to say and that you are
listening to me. Here are some mantras that
you can listen to. I'm going to recite manaso. I
learned it.
Animals, it
says, even insects and
animals
listen to you. I don't know if you are releasing
any animal or see an
animal. I like to sing to
wild animals. I like to make a
mandala offering. I see a deer, I stop, I stand up
and sing a mandala to it, a
mandala offering. Many times
they run
and stay. So you can put it in
your... I wanted to take my granddaughter to the
zoo.
Maybe it's been like 50 years since I've been.
Logically, I think that's something really...
But I said, "Okay, I'll go." My
wife said, "No
comment,
understood."
So I went around
and sang to the animals, to the
giraffe, to all of them. You can do that
when...  You know the animals,
you can now whisper things to them. It's the
same thing. You have to be creative,
have fun, you have to be a little
unusual, and that's perfect. Other people
get used to it,
they're not having fun.
You can say, "Look, I don't
want to say that, but
I'm weird, I'm not interested, go
ahead, I've done that all my life and it's
fun, and it's okay, and it's nice." You do
n't have to show that you're
kind of weird, but it's a whisper, you can do it, it's
fun, it's just
fun. Ah, that's the man who
sings to the giraffe.
Yes, you can put seeds in their hands when
you sing to them or make an offering of
something. You
can plant a
seed,
sing. Then, obviously, if you're somewhere
else, whether in the
park and people are there, that's not
closed off at all.
There's a great
tradition in the
monastery that speaks to many.
There are
groups of
people who pay the monks to
come and recite
and
perform in people's homes.
Supposedly,
people are supposed to be around listening. This
is an ancient Buddhist tradition.
So, I grew up in a temple. I was
there for 25 years.
We used to...  A couple of times a
week, usually, it's like, when monks come to
someone's house, they make a
pretty big comma, you recite those prayers
in their
homes. The abbot was a Mongolian who was
blind and very, very
fat because he loved chom chom, and
he would say, "Let's make chom chom." Okay,
very
good. I remember he was carrying a chom chom and
said, "I already said, '
We're
late. We should
start. The women should start at
noon, and we should start eating at
another time.' So, we were
a little
rushed now, and he said, 'I brought a
scripture,' but he said, 'I have an idea. Let's split it up.
I'll give each of them a few pages, and then they
recite it, and we can eat much
faster. But each of them will recite something
different. You don't
know,
Diador de Diam.' I
was like, 'Wow, I've never
read it before. I'm so cool.' And every time we went somewhere,
I tried to have
different pages. It's like, for the first
time, you
can do
that. Here it is: 'Be careful.'
When you go to a family's house
to say
prayers, it means, 'Be
careful.' It is
true that Lord Buddha used the
Diamond Path to become
Buddha in one lifetime. And by the way, there is
a  Discussion on the Diamond Path
in the text:
How many Buddhas reached
the Diamond Path without using it? How many Buddhas
did?  Taking the
Diamond Path and the answer is everyone uses the
Diamond Path there is no one who
became Buddha if he hadn't used the
path we all know that this
Buddha the path
a very heroic story we all know that he
But
exchange this means he
made secret mantras to
feed himself but secret mantras to get there
if we can do
that Did he go to people's houses
and exchange mantras for food? He says they do
n't make mantras in
homes, the result is
food is to feed us, no, do
n't sell it.
People
worry, you can sell books, the
wrong thing. It depends on
you, it's a
terrible business, diamonds are very expensive.
I'm saying with this that it's not a
good business if you want money. If
you want a business, don't sell the Dharma, sell something
else, sell jewelry or something like that.
He says
here, don't sell the
Dharma, you can charge money here, this is
my answer: you can charge
money, you can ask for donations for
yourself during a tour.
People always
ask for donations, you
sit like he's about to... my
answer
is: do you want a
donation for his 30-30 program? Then
come
with me, I'll
seat you right here.
travel agency and we'll talk
to them and
sorry, pick up your suitcase quickly from
here. We all have expenses and we can't
cover the
teachings. They've always been
free, but for me it's a lot of pressure, and for
people it's very difficult to
raise the money, and that also
takes up a lot of our
time. Everything is free, you
don't have to give anything, but if you can
help, we could translate more books,
we could do more
teachings. The Vietnamese just
donated
about
140,000 to the
volunteer group. The best thing was that I didn't even have to
ask, they just did it. I didn't have to
stop working,
and the people who organize these tours
don't
enjoy it. You feel like a
prostitute sometimes. No, seriously, when I go,
please give me money for
this, but you have, we are grateful. You
have a program to continue
the teachings of
God. We've called it "
daily." So we
would finish, how much did we say, 30
years? In 7 years we
would finish, that's 9
years. Well, it's 9 years.
We're going to make a video of 100
meditations. We're going to make 100
videos. We're doing something this week. We'll do
one tomorrow.
[Music] We do
enough
measurements, we do very well, everything from the
old books has been stable, but we have
n't done enough
measurements, we haven't recorded them, and there are
about 100 measurements, and we're going to
record
1000 that we're going to leave in a
half-hour period so we can maintain the
attention period. If it was going to be
4 hours, Med
H asking, I can't even do
things, we're going to do them, and you can, for the rest of your
life, you'll have
options, you'll decide on meditating.
Med, we need help, just register,
please use the
registration code on your card. It's
like you have 200
subscriptions to different kinds of
things, like a
good movie on some
streaming service. I say, "Oh, what do I care?" $ a
month, I send it to you just to watch
a movie, but after 20 years, that's it. I think we
should say
with, "Think, it's like another
service," so please help us. It's not
much a month.
Hac can fly all over the place, Al and his
gang can go help other
people, and we can keep this
free. That's our
intention. It's not free; this is for the
cabins, the food.
Trying to get money out of the DMA is like
asking a  Asking a king or
queen to come down and clean
the trash is not appropriate. It's
like asking a king or queen to
go and do the same thing.
Keep your motivation
high at 7 a.m. The
question and answer session
means the gift of God. We are
focusing
here on giving the gift of God. We must
now
push God to people
every day around the world. I can't
remember where
12 years ago I told the same
story. So if you're in the
Diamond Way classes, you think
Kesla knows what she's
doing. She's trying to give you this
story two or three times. But if not, you
can simply say, "She's
getting old. I don't care."
Well, I've forgotten the story to
tell. So, I took the bus to New
York for about 19
years. People tell me it was about
an hour and 45 minutes. It was 4 hours to
a
bus because I wanted to give all that money
to the library. The
Asian delegate, and so I gave it to the monastery
too. So it was 19 years that
I took the bus and stood there
during thunderstorms.
So one day, coming back
The bus stopped
quite far from home, so I could walk for
a few
hours. He came to get
me. I was in that bar, and
there was a lady there dancing
on the bar. There were
all these guys
there. I was reading this part of it, and I
thought, well, it
says that whenever you're sitting with
someone, try to talk to them in a
way. I
was watching all these drunk guys
and the dancing, and I thought, have
you ever heard
about it? If you have ways, you can always
say "Hello," and
you can... So when
you're helping people, that's
one of those activities. Wherever you
find yourself, whether
accidentally or not, now don't waste time.
Try to learn something, or try to speak
something. We had it yesterday. We did
a ritual. There
are
64 songs.
Many times they say there are 60, but one
of them is about being able to talk
to anyone in their
own language. You can try to
learn... What is it doing?
Ah, it's
that...
[Music]
there's always some kind of thing to learn. You will
speak to people. It means Russian,
Spanish,
learn to speak to people in their own language. It's
a skill from
around
1920. You are a...  It's not very limited to the
DMA (presumably referring to a specific department or group) that they do
good because monks shouldn't own
possessions or money, and I think that's been implemented
in
recent years. In my monastery, everyone
has their own house, their own apartment. They
pass it on to their students. So, if there's
private property, I think that's not a good
system. The
school is where my teacher was, and he was
vice-president
there. You have to be changing rooms
every time you live in a place. It's
now
private property. You have your own apartment,
and then you pass it on to someone. But
monks and nuns aren't supposed to own
many things, so what a monk can give you
is the dhara. It
means it comes from here to you. A
very easy way for people to give you a
lot of money is if someone gives you a
red envelope with 0.000 and you didn't ask for it. They just praised you.
Well, as a monk or nun, you can share
what you have. You can share
money. You can share money with
other people. There's
a
second-generation calling of
nuns. I
like it. I'm not trying to
sell you the
benefits of sharing what you
have. I'm trying to convince you
that it's going to hurt you to keep
things, and that's great. He says, "I'm not trying to..."
Donate money. I
'm simply telling you that if you keep it, it will
hurt you. That's very interesting. If you keep it,
if you think you can, if you
think
keeping it will hurt you. But now,
the point is to keep it. I don't buy things. I
have an old house, old clothes. Just recently, I got it.
From what I can see, it's not very
good. But if I have money, I like to
use it. I like a new book, to
build a new one,
or something similar. So, I'm trying
to convince you to do something. I'm
trying to get you to understand the
act. I'm trying to convince you that
keeping things is a
strategy. When you keep them, my
friend, in the diamond business
in
Mumbai, he started a
diamond business. We started it together in India, and
he was one of the biggest in the world.
And he used to say, "Money
likes to move. We shouldn't keep
money in a bank account. You shouldn't
have it in your pocket.
Money likes to move." And that will
help more people. I
'm not trying to convince you to
be generous; I'm simply
saying that...  And annoying. It's
sitting on the Dino even though you're going to
die. Then that
money will go to someone else. It's
silly. Don't let the money just sit
there doing nothing while you're
sitting on it. Then he died and didn't
help anyone. The money
often flows too fast. That's
okay too. Sometimes my wife says, "We ca
n't pay this bill." Ah, we'll work it out. It's
better that it flows too fast than to hold on to
it. Holding on to it doesn't help.
It's silly.
Then we'd all be poor. We have to
let it flow, let it
circulate for the benefit of all.
We're going to pause here and
do the Q&
A section. Please don't hit
anyone with the
microphone box on purpose. If you need to go to the
toilet, you can. And that's the
first question,
and it's a fun,
complicated question. It says, can you explain
how we move
from the instinctual taste of emptiness to the
sixth taste of emptiness?
And how dependence is different
from those two? To help our
students understand both differences,
the
difference between the two forms of emptiness
within the middle way, between the
middle way and the
high way.  I like to
call them the two
sides of the coin of the
Middle Way, the lower path, which would be
five. They
believe that basically you can think of it as
us interpreting the
world, how the world appears to
you. It's an interpretation. Many
different people
have raw information. Now,
for example, there's a glass with
pink liquid. So the
raw information says, according to the lower Middle Way,
it's exactly the same for
everyone in this room: there's a glass
with pink liquid, and that's on the other side,
not my side, but the other side. There's
raw information that appears before,
and that's
pink in color, and a shape within.
Then I interpret different
attempts, precisely
if it's healthy. It seems to be
almond milk, almond milk with strawberries, and
zero
carbs. So, I don't know, for
someone else it might be. If you don't know, that's what
people in the
Middle Way are like. I get all kinds of
emails, and it's about what you're
drinking.
Seriously, once you enter the
master role, because people see all sorts of
terrible things, the same liquid, and they see a
margarita. That tells us more about the
person who
sees it. If you see a margarita, maybe you
're drinking margaritas. No,
I'm in the Inner Middle Way school.
Everything has a certain
seed, and now there's information in a
group.
There are roses, and nobody made it; it's
just what was in hand. I
'm not making the
pink liquid as I interpret it, as I take it. That's the thing. If I've been
drinking
margaritas for a long time, if I've been on
a diet for too long,
kilos. If you've been on a diet for a long
time, you're going to say, "Oh, that's
a kind of healthy lifestyle," something like that.
So, in the Inner Way school,
in worldview number
five, people are interpreting
the raw information that's
there. If the raw information is
there, and we
interpret it in different ways, and that's
the emptiness. The emptiness of this
pink liquid is that it could be an
almond drink, it could be a
margarita—it all depends on your seed.
But the pink liquid doesn't depend on your
seed. The pink liquid is information.
We're all experiencing a
pink liquid distinct from
our seeds. That's it. Now let's go with
the sixth worldview. The sixth is that
even though the raw information
comes from you, even though that pink liquid
comes from you, there are many people who wouldn't
see pink, and there are many people who would
n't see liquid either.  People
who might see this as a
little thing or something, there's no reason
to say, "Just because it's pink,
that pink comes from its own side." And the
highest school of the Middle Way, the
Sixth Worldview, says that even
raw information comes
from different seeds. You wouldn't even
see pink. You would
n't see the shape of a glass;
you'd see a different shape and a different color.
Everything about your perceptions comes
from your seeds. There's nothing that comes from
its own side, not even the
color pink or the shape. You're also
making that. And that's a difference between
flavors. As you go,
yes, raising the six flavors of
emptiness,
they become more and more
inclusive. And they help you much more. And you
can understand that even the
colors you see come from
you. You'll be a much better
person. You'll be kinder and
sweeter. Even the colors come from you. Everything comes
from you. There's nothing about another.
Even your face and the color of
your lips don't come from anything else. It's all
your fault. Excuse me, but every fool you
meet is a
direct perception. I see this
overwhelming. Seeing this
boyfriend, even the colors come from it,
even
how they act,
according to the...
What they would say: If the mental state is
affected by alcohol or
illness, then the
raw information is there on its own. That is the fifth
vision
of the mind: it must be clear, it must not be either.
Thank you. The first of the
perfections,
the first of the
perfections, is
sharing. And the first of the
civil friends, by the
way, organized a very
beautiful talk. He and I spoke with
Marine, who
invented that organization and
cleaning program in Japan. We had a very good time.
I think we spoke for about an hour
with her, and the three of us had
a chat together. It's fun to be able to
see someone so disorganized
talking with such
organized people. But it was a very
beautiful interview that we had, and perhaps we can
repeat it.
In the first of the
four magnets, or ways to attract disciples, it is to
attract them with
material things. If you are ready,
you must attract students, and the first thing is to
help in an economic and financial way,
to offer them things. By the way, in Latin America, it is
people who are going to go on
tour. The key is to
give so that people come.
If you really want to
attract, then the first rule is to be
generous.
The original courses for
years, I paid for  All for years,
but if you want to be a
teacher from the
beginning, so that people come to
classes, you must be
generous. Don't give money; I don't have things that
are cheap, but high quality,
high-quality sodas. Spend time
thinking about things and putting in costly effort
to be able to help your students, and if a
student doesn't have money
or is having a difficult financial situation, help them. That's
the first step to being a
teacher: being willing to help your students in any
way and also whatever they
need. Help them, help them to be able to. The
difference between that and
perfections is perfection. When
we talk about the four methods
to attract
disciples, it's the same. It's the same
perfection, dear, but in short, the
goal of giving is precisely to attract
people to come, and the first
perfection is more general; it's all
kinds of things. In fact, in the first
perfection, you're still trying to get
people to come. But in 10,000
years, when he gave his body to the
tigress, it's the same as giving donuts to the
first
student. But it's going to be a period of time, perhaps a longer one.
The first of the
four methods is...  That's
true, it has purposes.
Don't be out of it.
That's just how things are, that's just
how the world is. Spend some time,
make sure you have
high-quality soft drinks, that you have
enough, that you're ready to
clean up afterward because they're not going to
help you pick up and
clean. Relax. Have fun. You're not
like your mom. Your mom doesn't say, "Look,
you know how many full breasts of milk I've already given you, do you
want a lap of milk?"
Simply, then, master of the
[Music] of, do
n't get half weird about it,
just
give it. That's the business we're in, it's
what we do. Let's have a drink,
see you around in half an hour.